This is part 6.3, the video ad types. All right, let's jump right into this.
So the way I've broken it down are seven different app types and then
fi four different ads styles. All right? So you may have heard of these,
you may have not. But over here we have the spokesman anchor,
the product demo, social proof ad, dynamic ads, case studies,
lifestyle unboxing. And then on the right,
the ad style is how the video is produced and edited.
We have u G c commercial branded mashup,
and then drop style dropship style.
So depending on your familiarity with production, um,
this may be already known to you, but, uh, maybe you, you've seen these ads,
you don't realize what they're called or what they're, you know,
what the name of them is. But, uh, let's go over them one by one.
So before I get into that, actually,
it's really important to see that you can actually combine different ad styles,
uh, ad types with different styles. I think this is a thing that, um,
is only for people who produce a lot of content,
is you can take an ad lifestyle video and make it U G C. Um,
you can, you can do any of these combinations and get a wildly different result.
Okay? You can take a spokesperson anchor video, which is, you know,
talking head with a person behind the screen or an actor,
and then make that commercial, or you can make that U G C,
or you can make that more of a mashup.
So there's tons of different potentials here,
product demo to drop ship style.
So let's go into more of what this actually looks like. All right,
lemme move my face over here. Okay, so the spokes pin anchor video,
highly engaging video featuring a product, explaining the product,
and highlighting its features. Ideal length is 92 seconds.
So this is a video, let me see if I can pull this up right here. All right,
let's watch this video real quick. Just the first, you know, couple seconds.
All right. So I think you guys have probably seen these ads before,
but a spokesperson video is usually done. Um, you know,
with, with higher quality, lemme move my face down here, whatever,
doesn't matter. Um, higher quality production, you know,
these are high budget stuff and they take a lot of time to produce,
but I would say as a brand,
if you've reached a certain point in your business and you wanted to really d
differentiate yourself, uh, spokesperson ads are really solid. Um,
but typically I would say editors are not doing a lot of spokesperson ads.
I mean, at this high quality level, uh, depends if you're shooting, you know,
if you have a spokesperson as a brand,
you're doing a lot of their edits or YouTube videos. I, I would say it's,
it's almost equivalent to that. But, you know,
when you're doing higher production stuff,
you're dealing with bigger footage and higher quality stuff,
so it could slow down your computer.
Next we have product demonstrations, and this is a,
probably the most common video.
You're gonna see these highlight the product features and, and, uh,
and benefits and demonstrates the value to, to the customer.
Ideal length is 25 seconds. So let's watch this quick video.
All right, so pretty straightforward, right? It's showing the,
it's demonstrating the product live. Uh, obviously this is a, a bath mat,
and you're just showing all the different use cases and the features of it.
Pretty straightforward there. You see these all the time. You know,
these are very drop shipping style. This is,
I would say this is a drop shipping style. And, um, you know, it, it,
it's what you see on any platform these days. Amazon.
Next one is social proof ads. All right?
These are opinions of brands or products by consumers, influencers,
blogs leveraged to create trust between consumers and brands. All right, uh,
ideal length here is 44 seconds. These could be,
these are just one potential style for a social proof ad.
And these are actually image ads, but these could be animated,
these could be motion graphic style ads. Um,
a social proof ad could also be a U G C mashup of multiple testimonials into one
video, which is probably the most common one,
which we'll actually go through how to edit those style videos.
But if there's any sort of, um,
customer review happening or any type of quote happening,
these are considered social proof ads. Uh,
these are great for middle of the funnel, um, but you know,
they could be used as top funnel as well. Just depends on the impact of, of the,
the message itself. If the testimonial is really strong, it could,
it could resonate, uh, you know, deeply with a customer,
and it could be used as a top funnel. And, okay,
these are dynamic ads.
These are compu computer generated creative assets to test,
to ab test at scale. All right, so these are your, I would say these are your,
so common, you know, these are your, like, I don't like these ads, um,
because they're just very generic looking. They look very, uh, what's the word?
Like stock or, uh, I don't know,
there's just no personality of 'em. Uh,
you get banner blindness with these types of ads,
and these are actually the ads that perform the least. Um,
ideal length for these guys are nine seconds. But again, you know, it, it's,
it's very clearly an ad.
And I think these days you want to create ads that don't really look like ads if
you want them to be most effective. All right,
number five are case study ads,
controlled studies or testing of products proving superior performance or
increased quality of life. Ideal 44 seconds. There's a lot of potentials here,
but I included in us first them,
which is kind of like a case study where you're comparing your product to
another product and why your results are better.
You can actually do real case studies of people's transformation.
If you see in the one on the right, how I lost 86 pounds and found my true self.
So anything that you're demonstrating that your product is superior, uh,
would be considered a case study ad.
And those are very impactful 'cause people are skeptical and they want proof and
they wanna see that it actually works and they wanna see that there's data
behind it and they wanna see, you know, it's not fake.
So that's a good opportunity to, to drive more sales, um,
through trust. Alright, next you have your lifestyle videos.
This is showcasing the product being used in everyday life.
A ideal length here is 21 seconds,
and I think these are the most commonly shot by like videographers. Um,
I've worked with a lot of videographers, but lifestyle is, um, you know,
cinematic. It's very, uh, lemme go back, I'm sure. I mean,
you've seen these, these are like probably the most common, uh, styles,
like for a, for a creative.
But I would say I don't really do lifestyle too much, um, here and there,
but I prefer, I really do prefer U G C. That's kind of my strength.
Everyone has their strengths, uh, in terms of shooting,
but these are fun to edit 'cause they're clean.
You make 'em really nice and really clean, very minimal.
So from an editing standpoint, they don't require too much. And it's, yeah,
I would say most of the work happens in production for,
for products like this or for, for lifestyle shoots. Next,
you have unboxing. This is pretty straightforward, showing the product,
packaging and features. Uh, you've seen these everywhere, obviously.
Uh, still pretty self-explanatory. Showing the box, showing the product itself.
Sometimes you have a voiceover over these, but these are probably super, super,
the most common, uh, you'll see around, around your, uh, your newsfeeds.
Okay, so here are the different ad styles that over,
I would say just over the years, I've seen
as like ways that you can, uh,
you can shoot something or you can edit something. So number one is U G C,
obviously shot with a phone done in a very
social media format. So you're adding TikTok captions, um,
making it look native to the platform. Number two, you have commercial.
This is gonna, this means you, you shot it with a commercial camera,
you shot it in a studio. You, you made sure you had lighting D dialed in. Um,
and, and, and, you know, it looks like it belongs on tv. Like,
I feel like commercial is just, oh, that's a TV commercial like that,
that should, that could be played, uh, that could be played on tv. And I,
I'll double that as a commercial. Ad number three are branded.
These are the ones that, you know, they're very controlled, like, you know,
it's all about the brand. Um, and with the titles, with the captions,
with the colors, with the overlays, um,
that's kind of the, uh, the look and feel here. Actually, let's play this video.
All right. So you can tell that one's very branded. Uh,
they shut on a backdrop and they just kept it very minimal,
but they're focusing really on their, their product. Um,
oops, keeps doing that. So next one is mashup.
And that's very similar to the example that I shared with you. Uh,
where was this hook?
Alright, I'm not gonna play the whole thing,
but you can see that I mashed up a lot of different footage here. Uh,
because the content was primarily U G C.
They have a lot of influencers and content creators.
So it was my job to basically take that footage and create a story from it.
And I think mashups are so effective because you're,
it doesn't really matter so much about the quality of all the content.
It doesn't matter at all. What matters is the story that you're telling.
And if you're able to take the right clips and the right lines from the U
G C, you can create something very powerful and it, it has performed very,
very well for them. Lastly, you have your drop ship style. All right,
um, lemme see if I have this example. I guess I don't,
but I would say this is like the very spammy style.
There's not really any brand to it. Uh, it's not U G C either.
It's kind of in the middle where it's just kind of like quick text trying to get
your attention. Um, and I'll include some,
some links in there for you because this is a very,
you know, we started off, I started off as dropshippers, so I,
I know these styles by heart, but, uh,
I'll include some links of dropship dropship style ads. Um, and they work for,
you know, they still work,
but you're gonna attract a certain type of person each time. You know,
I would say each one of these ads will attract a different type of consumer.
So it's really nice to test all of these.
If you have the production capability, if you have the budget,
if you have the resources, depending on, uh,
you know where you are in the company, if it's your company,
then definitely I would test them. All.
The ad type and ad style will always depend on the brand strategy and vision.
You as an editor will be responsible to match that strategy. I just said that.
But, you know, depending on what that strategy is, man,
if we're going for commercial, make sure it's clean, make sure it's nice.
If we're going for branded, same thing.
Make sure you have branded elements in there. Branded colors.
If we're going for U G C,
make sure that thing looks native af you're using native stuff, native captions.
Uh, if you wanna mashup, you know, make sure you, you, you're not,
you're not so focused on, on design and brand.
You're more focused on telling the story, uh, and drop ship.
If you wanna just strictly grab attention and, and get people to click,
then follow that strategy. All right,
that wraps up part six. I hope you enjoyed it. It was a, it was a lot,
but I hope by now you have a clear understanding of what is out there and what
possibilities you can create as an editor. I will see you in part seven,
staying organized.